## Gabriela D'Souza

0406968191

<u>G.DSouza0191@gmail.com</u> https://gdsouza0191.wixsite.com/mysite

## **Career Snapshot**

Senior Economist	CEDA	Nov 2018 – present
Data Analytics Consultant	Self employed	March 2018 – present
Senior Advisor, Innovation policy and	RMIT University	July 2015 – July 2018
data analytics		
Research Associate	Grattan Institute	July 2014 – July 2015
Research Assistant	CeRAPH	Jun 2013 – Jun 2014
Research Officer/Research Assistant	NATSEM	Jan 2012 – Jun 2013
Academic Intern	NATSEM	Aug 2011 – Dec 2011

# **Education and Training**

Master of Economics	Monash University	2018
Bachelor of Applied Economics	University of Canberra	2011

#### **Technical skills**

- Proficiency is using a number of statistical packages in R to build models, create attractive data visualisations, and interactive plots and apps
- Skilled in using STATA to develop econometric models
- Experience in using Excel to analyse data
- Experience in using other programs like SAS, SPSS, and AMOS for building structural models
- Experience in using Github to share and collaborate on code

# **Employment History**

#### **Senior Economist**

Committee for the Economic Development of Australia (CEDA) November 2018 – present

Conducting research on immigration and labour market related issues.

- Analysing publicly available datasets and conducted modelling to estimate the effects of various interventions
- Writing reports to summarise findings from analysis
- Presenting to CEDA audiences around the country and speaking with media to raise the profile of the organisation

# **Data Analytics Consultant**

Self Employed

March 2018 – present

- Advising education institutions on techniques that can be used to identify the impact of their program on students
- Using a Melbourne based ed-tech firm's administrative data to draw insights about performance and outcomes of their students
- Building econometric models to evaluate the impact of education programs

### Senior Advisor, Innovation policy and data analytics

RMIT University July 2015 – July 2018

- Working with the Shape RMIT team, developing the metrics used in the strategic plan
- Collecting data from various sources and analysing this to produce visualisations and reports for use by the Vice Chancellor's Office
- Modelling the impacts of government's education policy measures on students
- Building models of student outcomes to identify student's most likely to drop out of university

#### **Research Associate**

**Grattan Institute** 

June 2014- July 2015

Working on the Productivity Growth and Higher education teams analysing current policy settings and investigating opportunities for regulatory reform

- Working with limited data to project and forecast the effects of change in policy
- Researching the impact of lost superannuation accounts on costs to Australians
- Communicating results of analysis in the appropriate format
- Engaging in meetings with key stakeholders including key policymakers

### **Research Assistant**

Centre for Research and Action in Public Health (CeRAPH), University of Canberra June 2013 – June 2014

Developing a social marginalisation model and assisting in building a latent variable model to analyse attitudes to climate change.

- Identifying and negotiating access to data sources
- Conducting analysis and developing models to shed light on seemingly immeasurable problems
- Writing high quality reports and delivering presentations to a variety of audiences

### **Research Officer/Research Assistant**

National Centre for Social and Economic Modelling (NATSEM), University of Canberra January 2012 – June 2013

Working on a broad range of issues including youth social exclusion, education and innovation, workforce vulnerability and homelessness.

- Conducting literature reviews and working on fast-paced consultancy projects
- Analysing data and constructing models to better understand public policy problems and interventions
- Collaborating with other researchers, including drafting sections of major reports
- Presenting research at various conferences and workshops

### **Academic Intern**

National Centre for Social and Economic Modelling (NATSEM), University of Canberra August 2011 – December 2011

Building a cost model for residential aged care and forecasting this over the next three decades under the Health, Aging and Disability Team, which was used as background for important PhD research on the same topic. In addition I also researched subjective well-being among agricultural communities in the Murray-Darling basin, which was used in a journal article.

# Other Experience

Volunteer Tutor	AMES Australia	Sep 2015- Nov 2017
Intern	E-magine Foundation, Australia	Aug 2011-Dec 2011
Airport Operations, Summer Staff	Etihad Airways, Abu Dhabi, UAE	May 2011- Jul 2011
President (Volunteer)	International Students' Association, University of Canberra	Jan 2011-Dec 2011

Vice President (Volunteer)

International Students'
Association, University of Canberra
University of Canberra
Students' Association

Oct 2010-Oct 2011

International Student

ACT government

Jul 2011-Jun 2012

### **Publications and Presentations**

Ambassador (Honorary)

 D'Souza, G. (2018) A higher-education bubble? The wage effect of the demand driven system, Working Paper.
 D'Souza, G. (2017) Relative Success of Australia's new migrants, working paper (thesis towards the completion of masters in economics degree)

- D'Souza G. (2017) Relative Success of Australia's new migrants, presented to the Monash Faculty of Business and Economics
- Abello, A., Cassells, R., Daly, A., D'Souza, G. and Miranti, R. (2014) Youth Social Exclusion in Australian Communities: A new index, Social Indicators Research, (submitted, awaiting review)
- Abello, A., Cassells, R., Daly, A., D'Souza, G. and Miranti, R. (2013) 'Developing an index of Youth Social Exclusion for Australian Communities', presented at a panel discussion to the Australian Conference of Economists, Perth, 9<sup>th</sup> July 2013.
- Cruwys, T., Berry, H.L., Cassells, R., Duncan, A., O'Brien, L.V., Sage, B. and D'Souza, G. (2013). 'Marginalised Australians: Characteristics and Predictors of Exit over Ten years 2001-2010', University of Canberra.
- Keegan, M., D'Souza, G. and Cassells, R. (2014) 'Superannuation adequacy with voluntary contributions: a comparison of living standards', Conference Paper, Australian Conference of Economists
- D'Souza, G., Tanton, R., Mohanty, I. and Thurect, L. (2013) 'Geographical Analysis of the risk of Homelessness', report prepared for Swinburne University of Technology, National Homelessness Research Agenda 2009-2013
- Tanton, R., D'Souza, G., Abello, A., Mohanty, I. and Thurect, L. (2015) 'Geographical Analysis of the risk of Homelessness using a composite index', Social Indicators Research (Submitted)
- D'Souza, G. and Miranti, R (2013) 'Workforce Underemployment A literature review', NATSEM working paper (Unpublished)
- D'Souza, G. and Cassells, R. (2012). 'Youth Social Exclusion: A New Social Index for Australians'. Presented to the Australian Institute of Family Studies, 25 July 2012.
- D'Souza, G. and Cassells, R. (2012). 'Youth Social Exclusion: A New Social Index for Australians'. Presented to the NATSEM Child and Youth Wellbeing workshop, 5th September 2012
- Cassells, R., Abello, A., Nepal, B. & D'Souza, G. (2012) 'Smart Australians: Education and Innovation in Australia', AMP.NATSEM Income and Wealth Report, Issue 32
- D'Souza, G., Cassells, R., Daly, A & Abello, A. (2012) 'Youth Social Exclusion A New Index for Australian Communities', NATSEM Working Paper (Forthcoming)
- Abello, A., Cassells, R., Daly, A., D'Souza, G., and Miranti, R. (2014) 'Youth Social Exclusion in Australian Communities: A New Index', *Social indicators research*, 1-26.
- Cassells, R., Miranti, R., Abello, A., Mohanty, I., D'Souza, G., Watson, I. & Vidyattama, Y. (2012) 'Women in NSW 2012', report commissioned by the New South Wales Office for Women

### Assisted in the research and drafting of the following reports

 Norton, A. and Cherastidtham, I. (2015) The cash nexus: how teaching funds research in Australian universities, Grattan Institute

- Norton, A. & Cherastidtham, I., 2015, University fees: what students pay in deregulated markets, Grattan Institute
- Minifie, J., Cameron, T., and Savage, J. 2015, Super savings, Grattan Institute

# **Personal Activities**

- Working proficiency in Hindi and Arabic
- Committee member of the Young Professionals Victoria Network
  Accomplished pianist (up to Grade 7 Associated Board of Royal School of Music)